hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft as you
can see we're not doing a traditional
intro to this video because iskal has
been trying to put the rotten potato on
me for a little while now and I've
basically been standing still AFK for a
long time just watching him and waiting
to see if he's actually going to throw
the rotten potato on and it's actually
quite funny as you can see I'm outside
of dig straight down iskal is there he's
already thrown two items in my inventory
this item and this item tricked he's
definitely working out whether I'm
baiting him to with the potato I know
that he's got the rotten potato at the
moment so I'm playing the long game I've
been standing here for like 10 minutes
easily and I'm just waiting for him he's
tried three or four times now to throw
fake items in I'm waiting for him to
throw the potato and he's now currently
playing the game so I'm just gonna play
the long game and wait for him to throw
the potato and then I'm gonna I'm gonna
bait him and then he's gonna have to do
his own punishment this is gonna be so
good
foreign
we're about 10 minutes in now we're just
gonna wait here because I'm sure he
can't help himself
here he comes oh he's gonna do it I
could tell he's gonna do it no
checking the book to see if he can get
me I guess
the long game
the long game one
what was the punishment I didn't even
read it
what was it let's see punishment include
of Doom when describing things you look
at or create in your next episode at
least 25 times you just got got I guess
you can have this back and this back too
uh Take a Bow I'll take a bow well well
well I I I know you to be a prankster I
know you to be a mega troll I didn't
think that you would play the long that
was 30 minutes
I accidentally moved my camera at one
point I accidentally moved like my head
sight slightly and oh I'm pretty sure
you knew I was baiting you at that point
and then I was just like no if I just
leave it he's gonna he's gonna give in I
mean I did drop two did you see the
trick items yeah oh yeah I'm saying I
was sitting there in my inventory just
seeing it pop in I'm like nope that's
not it no that's you didn't even twig I
gotta say you deserve that one I just I
wish your punishment wasn't so on brand
you do that anyway way yeah I know but
while I was AFK I did see you playing my
new game uh dig straight down dude this
game is so popular there's so many
people I I noticed you you're making a
lot of money for Sahara I love it it's
great this isn't a Sahara project this
is this going into the Vault this is me
but also I don't actually this is the
worst thing about this dude I don't
think I'm making any profit oh oh yeah
because it costs Diamond doors yeah
well here's the thing for you so I dug
straight down twice I paid twice paid 10
diamonds in total yeah the first time I
came up with one Diamond profit and the
second time I had nine diamonds and then
I hit lava oh but I didn't see you guys
I managed no I managed to survive
placing a dirt block in the lava which I
I gotta say the move was pretty Pro I
survived with one heart yeah I think
that's that's meant to be game over so I
think I'm gonna add a quick rule here
that uh that's what I figured so here's
what I did as well there we go if you
hit lava you lose and must accept your
fate
yeah I kind of figured but because there
was no sign I salvaged the diamonds and
I actually renamed them so that they
would be fine well realistically they're
not mine either they would have ended up
in uh lava so yeah let's uh
yes nice there we go but you take five
you take five for the genius game and
I'll keep four I would have taken five
if I would have potatoed you but
geez the long game so now that we've got
iskau back with the potato thing that
was really really funny I now want to
draw your attention to what I said at
the end of last episode which was that I
wanted to make a secret lab but I forgot
I've totally already got a secret lab
and it's down here under my house so I
guess it's really not a secret as
everyone does know where it is but why
make a brand new lab when I've got one
right here so we're gonna use this and
we're gonna repurpose this for my next
invention and this invention is going to
change the course of hermitcraft history
so what we need to do is get rid of all
of this stuff because the Villager
breeding project has now moved outside I
think I figured out a real way to get
back my diamonds that have been
misplaced on the server this area has
now been repurposed and what we're going
to make is going to be amazing I've got
everything that I need right here in
order to make a way to get my diamonds
back
and I have no idea if this is actually
going to work and I'm not sure that it
makes a lot of sense what I'm doing
right now but just bear with me for two
seconds hopefully this will make sense
in a minute it may not be bigger on the
inside but I think that this machine
will be able to help us get our diamonds
back but there's a very specific
configuration so if you haven't guessed
already what I'm trying to make here is
a genuine Minecraft time machine and I
know what you're thinking green you
cannot travel back in time it's just not
possible well to those people I say
watch me I'm going to do it and we're
going to find out exactly what happened
to our diamonds now if my calculations
are correct all we need to do is spin
this round three times one
to
three and then we hit go and it should
take us right through
oh yeah that that didn't go well
I must have I definitely got something
wrong here maybe going through time just
isn't possible I I bet you all thought
that I was actually going to make it and
go through time
I don't think it's possible the machine
just breaks and that's it okay I think
I've repaired it oh wait I totally I
forgot the other Beacon you have to
understand that making this time machine
it's very very intricate and you need
every single part of it otherwise of
course it's not going to work
all right well maybe it'll work this
time then all right so put the time
machine back together
I think this should do it so
I think so let's just do a an outer
sweep everything is prepared the clock
is in place and now it's time so let's
do it powering up it's pretty simple but
if all of those are done and I think
three turns should do it one
two
three
okay
did that work
let's go out and check well it
definitely worked we have moved at least
so how do we check if we've actually
gone back in time that's the main thing
hold on we can actually check the build
off over here and maybe if it's
different yep well look there's Ren's
bus so we definitely went back based on
the bill of I forgot I forgot how crazy
it got after this so there's my house
looking pretty intact as it is apart
from the rocket going in let's go and
have a look around shall we we need to
know exactly when we are okay so we're
somewhere based on this we're somewhere
around episode 74 I would say or
something like that look there's
different people online iskau stress and
X are on and you can see by the times
that we have successfully gone back in
time and as you can see there are
different set of people online right now
so if we we should tell them high past
iskal
it's me future grin from the future
hello says X
it's me that extra says hello
he's got no idea little little will he
know what we've been up to
I'll just I'm just gonna leave them
being confused oh my gosh
Village agreeing
you're alive
I don't believe it
Village agree and I thought I'd lost you
I made a grave for you
I I buried you okay well we've
definitely got to take you with us so
that should be pretty easy if we grab
some random blocks uh oh no no no no no
no no no no no no no no no no no no no
no so if we lead him
in here what we can do is take him with
us to the Future there we go okay so if
we can if we can get Village agreeing in
here there's no reason why we can't just
take him with us but the real reason
that we're here is because around this
time somebody took all of my diamonds
and as you can see look they are here so
what we're gonna do is we are just going
to return these to my Ender Chest in the
future and then that takes care of all
of my diamond problems we'll also take
Village agreeing with us and all will be
right in the world so we just got to you
know I'm gonna break this door down so
we can get him in here there we go and
we need to return everything exactly as
it was so they don't know we were here
we've got all our diamonds
we've got villager green I think that's
pretty much it there's nothing else for
me to do except admire the state that
the Build-Off is in as now I can't
believe that this yeah I mean well this
is crazy enough but it got even more
crazy after this oh my goodness due to
the butterfly effect we definitely don't
want to cause too many changes in the
space-time Continuum we got what we came
for so let's skedaddle out of here all
right Village agreeing so let's ignition
ignition turn on
and let's turn it again and we'll go
back to where we were there we go oh
villager green are we back let's just
take a look outside ah villager group
where are we it looks like every time
you time Jump you end up somewhere else
which isn't good news for me because I
don't even know if we're in the right
place
so let's go for a little bit of a oh
well Cub fans on there's different
people online now ah that looks Vaguely
Familiar
with the ah there we go oh we're not too
far from herbertville that was quite a
jump look that is exactly where the time
machine was before and it's all well
it's all over groma grass now so the
time machine jumps not only in time but
in space as well but you cannot figure
out or know where you're gonna end up in
space so the time machine has ended up
all the way over here which which makes
getting you home Village agreeing quite
a difficult task I think because that's
a long way so I think what I'm gonna do
even like taking this down is a bit of a
nightmare so I'm going to take the power
source without the beacon it won't work
I'll take this and I'll take the clock
and then hopefully anyone finding this
will be fine I'm gonna figure out a way
to get you home
a little bit later because I could boat
all the way over but that's a really
really long way like imagine having to
put Villa degree in in a boat and boat
him all the way and by the way it'd have
to be in a straight line across the
grass
all the way over here and there's like
there's my mini game
so it oh that's a long way to go I think
villager green I'm just gonna leave you
there for now however
I think
well we didn't need this here lies
Village agreeing well that's not true
anymore so what we're gonna do was
um just joking he traveled through time
LOL so we can get rid of this because he
wasn't he wasn't even dead
feels feel silly now for having a
funeral unfortunately mini stress
actually yeah mean stress did actually
die
that's amazing but fortunately that does
mean
that I totally stole my own diamonds
I stole them it wasn't a glitch
oh I'm an idiot
that whole thing was absolutely
pointless I
went back in time
to find out where my diamonds went
took them from my own Ender Chest
and now I'm back in the present so
basically what happened was I stole my
own diamonds
to put them back exactly where they were
so uh
it all kind of makes sense now and
Village agreeing didn't die or get
killed by a zombie I stole him I don't
know if I'm an idiot or a genius so um
I feel kind of stupid but at this
this is really bittersweet
either way we've got some diamonds back
and that is 32 blocks of diamonds oh
that's amazing that's amazing I haven't
felt this Rich since jevin gave me all
of the diamonds for removing mumbo's
mustache
I wonder if we can use the time machine
for other things though maybe we can go
even further back in the season
hmm I reckon I reckon we should
experiment with it I'm Gonna Leave it
over there for now because Village
agreeing is is quite nicely trapped
inside and I don't really want him
wandering around and I also got 55
diamonds from dig straight down that's a
whole like that's basically another
stack I think this game has been really
really popular
so that brings our total up to 38 blocks
of diamond and six normal diamonds
I'd say we've done pretty well today to
be honest with you it might have been A
Journey For Nothing seeing as they were
my own diamonds
but it's the journey that counts isn't
it and look at the difference in the
build off between going back in time and
now we didn't have the dabbing penguin
or the or the dragon or the cloud it got
really insane and of course Ren's Bus
left the scene so it was pretty crazy
back then but I never thought honestly I
never thought it would end up with a
dabbing Penguin on the build off also
does that mean that if we go down back
into the laboratory
what's there just a just a hole left
here
hmm
well I guess we should definitely fix
this up I think that we should really
make a new place that's actually hidden
well I can't help but think that this
place has outlived its usefulness it's
been absolutely demolished maybe I'll
extend it and make a lab bigger or maybe
I should make a secret lab somewhere
else let me know in the comments what
you think however I have noticed that
this area obviously hermitville is where
I've been hanging out quite a lot but my
goodness look at this so I've got all of
these shulker boxes this is getting
almost as bad as my storage back at my
main base look I got storage up here I
got more storage over here this is
absolutely ridiculous and I'm I'm really
not sure I I need to do something about
this because look at all these shulker
boxes and there's even a pile of them
outside my base I'm getting uh
everywhere I go you can tell where I've
been
bit of a messy pup it seems either way
there's plenty of stuff to be getting on
with for example kind of need to set up
the way that you get from The Hermit
land sign to The Dig straight down mini
game but I don't know where everyone
else is planning on putting their mini
games but I think we can assume that
this Park's going to need some Pathways
and to be honest with you it doesn't
need to be well I'm only putting Stone
here for for now because I don't really
want to be the one setting the style I
kind of want this to happen fairly
organically however I do want at least
some infrastructure to be in place for
this project and I really can't wait to
see what other mini games are created
and I'm already trying to think of a new
mini game something that I hope will
make some diamonds much like dig
straight down did and if you've got any
ideas please let me know because I mean
that would be really really cool I know
that the other Hermits are really also
quite excited about hermit land and the
mini games that it will provide however
they are an awful lot of work I spent an
entire day making one small Mini-Game I
can't even think or imagine how long
ravager run took and this game which I
haven't even played yet this is iskal's
mini game so I think there's a lot of
potential here and I can't wait to see
where it goes but yeah I need to finish
off like a pathway and you can kind of
see hermit land taking shape it's got a
natural Island almost because the river
goes around here goes all the way
think over here whoa
Scar's working on something don't want
to spoil that and you can see the River
Works its way round up until this point
pretty much so there's a pretty large
natural area where the Mini-Game
District can be and I guess it can go as
far as it needs to be
wait what's this maybe it's not open yet
oh oh this is zaf's mini game where
you've got you've got a Crouch
everywhere but it also doesn't look
particularly finished there's no signs
or anything so no instructions either
way I think that that is all we have
time for in today's episode it was a
pretty interesting episode unfortunately
there will not be another episode of
hermitcraft for at least a week so just
be aware of that it may take a little
while for the next episode to come out
but it definitely will don't worry so be
sure to leave plenty of ideas in the
comments section for what we should do
on hermitcraft next because I mean
there's loads of things we can do we can
obviously now time travel which would be
awesome maybe we should go back even
further or we could build some mini
games in Hermit land thank you very much
for watching and good bye